<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Davis Sailing Team</title>
    <link>http://davissailingteam.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Davis Sailing Team</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://davissailingteam.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5&gt; Coming soon &lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;img/work/proj-4/bylaws.pdf&#34;&gt; Bylaws&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; Minutes and Budget Coming Soon &lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;!--
&lt;a href=&#34;http://davissailingteam.com/index.php/download_file/view/315/119/&#34;&gt;Bylaws&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://davissailingteam.com/documents/general-meetings/&#34;&gt;Minutes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://davissailingteam.com/documents/budget/&#34;&gt;Budget&lt;/a&gt;
![min](img/work/proj-4/img1.jpg)
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5&gt; About &lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a member of the Davis Sailing Team, you receive unlimited sailing access and eligibility to participate in regattas. We practice every week in Sacramento, and travel all over the country to participate in regattas. We travel as far as Washington and Hawaii and as close as Sacramento and San Francisco for regattas. So come and sail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; Eligibility &lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a current student and in good standing at University of California, Davis you are eligible to join the team. You do not need prior experience to join but you must know how to swim.You must also be a member of our host sailing club, Lake Washington Sailing Club (LWSC), which entitles you to many other benefits. Don&#39;t worry about not being a LWSC member, the team will assist you with this application process.

If you are an undergraduate student you will be eligible to sail in inter-collegiate and club events. However, if you are a graduate student, you can only compete in club events. However, everyone is encouraged to come to practice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; Fees and Dues &lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Davis Sailing Team has tri-annual quarterly dues of $130, and summer dues of $40 (for undergraduate students). For graduate students, community members, and alumni dues are $40 per quarter. For more information on dues feel free to contact our treasurer Cynthia Shyvers by emailing her at davis.sailingteam@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-1/img1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Membership&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4&gt; Commitment &amp; Experience &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; Do I need experience to join? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No experience is required! We will teach you everything you need to learn to be a competitive sailor!
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; When are practices? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practices are generally 3-4 hours every Saturday and Sunday. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In addition, we try to have weekday practices at the convenience of our members. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; When are regattas? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regattas are typically on the weekends and you can expect to be gone all day or all weekend depending on the location.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; How do I get to practices and regattas? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We carpools to all of our practices and events.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; Do I need to come to meetings?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes. Meetings have important info on regattas, practices, and activities.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To be an active team member make sure to come the weekly meeting every Thursday night at 9PM, in the MU Fielder Room.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if sailing&amp;rsquo;s for me. &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry! We give prospective members two free practices before they have to commit.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-3/img1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FAQ&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Gear &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;
Am I expected to bring my own gear?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are expected to bring your own gear. However, the team has a limited supply of extremely used foul weather gear that we loan to new sailors. We also have loaner life-jackets but they are not recommended for racing.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are many places to find affordable sailing gear, but if you can&amp;rsquo;t buy actual sailing gear try finding substitutes! (Dry fit, surf booties, and gardening gloves are great substitutes!)
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; If I don&amp;rsquo;t have any sailing gear what do I need to bring to practice? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring a bathing suit, towel, water, snacks, and a change of clothes. Plan to get wet.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-3/img2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FAQ&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Financial Information &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; Is the team a charitable organization?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes. We are a 501&amp;copy;3 organization.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; What are the member dues?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Undergraduates: $115 to Davis Sailing Team, $15 to Lake Washington Sailing Club.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graduates: $25 to Davis Sailing Team, $15 to Lake Washington Sailing Club.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; What are the regatta fees? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Each sailor has regatta fees included with club dues, excluding out of state Regattas such as Hawaii or the east coast.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; Is financial aid available? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The team has provided financial aid for sailors to compete in certain events. Financial aid is on an application based process that is evaluated for each event.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Prospective Freshmen &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; What role can my sailing play in the admissions process?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfortunately, a desire to sail for UC Davis cannot assist you in the admissions process.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; Can I get a scholarship for sailing?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No. Unfortunately our governing body, Inter-collegiate Sailing Association (ICSA) does not allow any sailor to receive a sailing related scholarship at any school.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; How cool are you guys?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extremely.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Sailing Aspects &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; What types of boats do we sail? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; We sail the Collegiate Flying Junior (CFJ.), which is a 14-foot, 2 person dinghy. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Additionally, we own a single-crew, Olympic-class Laser.
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;  Will I get to chose whether I get to skipper or crew?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes. We let our sailors chose which position they prefer. We encourage all sailors to be proficient in
 both positions. However, we encourage people to certain positions depending on their size, skill and enthusiasm.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; How much do I need to know about racing?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nothing! We will teach you everything that you need to know. That said, if you have race experience, that&amp;rsquo;s awesome!
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Teams &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; How do you make varsity? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The varsity team is chosen by skill. But don&amp;rsquo;t get discouraged if you haven&amp;rsquo;t sailed before. Half our varsity learned in college and already have the skills to race at the varsity level.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;  What is the difference between JV and Varsity?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The JV and Varsity teams practice, travel and race together. The only difference between the team is in scoring and eligibility. There are both varsity only and JV only regattas the team attends.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; What is the difference between a student organization and a club or varsity sport?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A student organization is student run, meaning we have no overseeing administrator. All our officers are students elected by our peers and are very aware of the students&amp;rsquo; budget, time, commitment and needs. The officers also gain valuable leadership and resume experience which they would not receive on a varsity sport.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As student organization, we are not only able to attend regattas without university restrictions but also maintain our equipment more efficiently. We cannot have our funding cut and we can receive donations.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-3/img3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FAQ&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Team Leadership &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; Who is in charge of the team? &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; A group of six students are elected to be the officers of the team. It is a great leadership opportunity and looks great on a resume.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; Do we have a coach?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our head coach is also our captain, who is both an officer and a student. The captain is in charge of organizing our experienced volunteer coaches (from outside the team) and all skipper crew placements.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h5&gt; Who designed this awesome website?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our intern, Sean Wu, who is also the team&amp;rsquo;s resident rocket scientist, pilot, &amp;hellip; basically he does everything.
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-3/img4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FAQ&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-5/freshitup-JieyuXiong.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fresh It Up&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-6/TimeLinePage-SergeyValiukh.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Timeline Page&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-7/img0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Weather Dashboard&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-7/img1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Weather Dashboard&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-7/img2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Weather Dashboard&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-7/img3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Weather Dashboard&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-7/img4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Weather Dashboard&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davissailingteam.com/work/proj-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/work/proj-8/stripes-co-NickZoutendijk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stripes &amp;amp; Co&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>